# Cameron E. Aaron

Studio City, California, United States | 818-385-7117 | <a href="mailto:cameronaaron1@gmail.com">cameronaaron1@gmail.com</a> | <a href="mailto:www.linkedin.com/in/kamisama">www.linkedin.com/in/kamisama</a>





# **ABOUT ME**

Cameron is a double major in Computer Science and Psychology with a minor in Cognitive Science and a Scholar in the Ammerman Center of Arts and Technology. He conducts both Artificial intelligence and Cognitive Neuroscience research. He is a Google product Expert and is currently a moderator for the official Google Android Beta subreddit.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

August 2020-Present

SpaceX. Hawthorne, CA, USA Aerospace Medicine Intern



Helping Hands Community, Mountain View, CA, USA

Jun 2020-September

### Field Operations Engineering Specialist

- Work on software engineering needs for the website to support field ops
- Create partnerships with the community to provide crisis relief to members of the community
- Support volunteers
- Work closely with the COO and Engineering team in order to address issues

Mar 2017 -Present



Google, Mountain View, CA, USA

- Works as a volunteer on Google product forums to help answer user questions
- Assist Customers by escalating cases to the correct team within Google to resolve
- Debug and troubleshoot user issues

Jun 2020 -September



#### Google Computer Science Summer Institute Section Leader

- Selected by Google to work as an algorithms TA and Student mentor for the Googles education team
- Responsible for mentoring and teaching a group of 50 students
- Ensured that my group had at least a 95% pass rate

July 2020 -Present



# Biology Research Fellow

- Executive research lead for 'Genomic Mutation of Sars CoV 2 Project'
- Spearheaded project proposal and executing research with 25+ member team
- Visualizing genetic mutation trends of SARS CoV 2 the virus that causes COVID-19
- Doing computational biology work relating to COVID- 19 specifically focusing on the evolution of the SARS-CoV-2 virus and examining the mutations of the virus by looking at regions of the viral genome and how they evolve using phylogenetic trees

Apr 2020 -Present



- Lead a team of UC Berkeley engineers
- Took ownership of the backend
- In charge of hiring new devs
- Successfully led team that won the Jacobs prize at UC Berkely
- Helped create an app that supplied PPE to much of central California

July 2020 -Present

CoronaWhy, San Francisco CA, USA Literature Review Interface Product Team

# **SKILLS**

#### Bioinformatics Research

Analyze single nucleotide polymorphisms Annotate Genomes Machine learning to Analyze medical imaging to better identify an abnormality **PCR** 

Collect and analyze EEG data

# Cyber Security

Network Penetration Testing Analyze code behavior down to assembly level language Red team blue team testing Social Engineering.

#### Software

Qualtrics Google G Suite Microsoft Office SPSS Adobe Creative Suite Apache spark Google Cloud Life Sciences Nessus Metasploit GitHub

# **Programming**

R

lava

**MATLAB** Unity (C#) HTML/CSS SQL Python Javascript

# Ruby on Rails

Scientific Research

EEG/ERP Eve-tracking Reach-tracking Behavioral testing Scientific writing Literature reviews Survevs Statistical inference Hypothesis testing Multivariate statistics Choice-Based Conjoint (CBC) Log analysis

Data visualization

+ Leading a product team and subject matter experts in exploring multiple projects related to the Kaggle CORD-19 task: "What do we know about vaccines and therapeutics from the COVID-19 and related coronavirus literature?"

## **Publications**

Variations 2E Finding the perfect Fit an article within Issue 2 (Spring 2019): The 2e Friendly Workplace

> The Bridges 2e Center for Research and Professional Development Panelist Vision & Leadership 2e Symposium 2019

#### Certifications

Cloud Engineering with GCP by Google Cloud

Google IT Support by Google

Architecting with Google Compute Engine Google Cloud

Google Cloud G Suite Administration Specialization

Google IT Automation with Python

# OTHER CAMERON STUFF

Google Product Expert
TEDx Event Organizer
2E Comic Book Creator
Google CSSI Section Leader
Volunteer at special need
school
Avid reader

Apr 2020 -Present BardoVR, San Francisco CA, USA Virtual Reality Game Development Intern

- + R&D into VR Systems
- + Content Creation
- + Psychological literature review
- + Game level development

Aug 2019 -Jan 2020 GitHub, San Francisco CA, USA

#### Software Engineer

- + Worked across teams to improve the customer's experience through engineering efforts
- + Worked on the GitHub.com
- + Worked in Ruby on Rails

Jun 2019 -Aug 2019

GitHub, San Francisco CA, USA

### **Community Support and Customer Success Engineering**

- + An interdisciplinary role that involved machine learning
- + Worked with cross-functional stakeholders in Operations, Product, Engineering, and
  - Legal to support product launches
- + Developed and executed support strategies that align with product goals
- + Provided operational suggestions to scale product support
- + Streamlined complex processes and implemented workflows designed to increase efficiency

May 2015 -Aug 2015



Wurrly, Santa Monica CA, USA

# QA Engineer

- + Performed Regression Testing for Wurrly application
- + HLS encoding
- + Developed test strategies, plans, and test cases
- + Developed Automation scripts
- + Took ownership of Bugs
- Verified fixes for defects
- + Tested and found bugs on the backend
- + Tracked down and figured out how to replicate user-reported issues

# **EDUCATION**

Aug 2017-May 2021



CONNECTICUT Connecticut College, New London, CT, United States of America

- + B.A. Computer Science
- \* B.A. Psychology
- + Minor Cognitive Science
- Certificate in Arts and Technology